# Emmaculate Wamboi

Nairobi, Kenya • linkedin.com/in/emmaculate • https://ewamboi.github.io/Portfolio/

## Summary

An experienced research analyst, digital marketer, and sales and marketing agent. Successfully optimized websites, delivering reliable results, increasing customer satisfaction by 25%, and managing teams with a 15% productivity boost.

Skilled in managing teams, resulting in an increase in productivity and a rise in conversion rates. Developed comprehensive client databases leading to a 25% improvement in customer satisfaction and an increase in repeat business.

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

#### CSV Research Solutions • Full-time • Aug 2021 - Present

# Research Analyst

- Developed a comprehensive client-based database, leading to a 25% improvement in customer satisfaction and a 20% increase in repeat business.
- Generated weekly and monthly reports to keep management informed on key performance metrics, leading to 30% of improvement in decision-making processes.
- Conducted data mining and analysis to improve decision-making processes and managed a team of 10 individuals, resulting in an increase in productivity and a 15% decrease in errors.

#### SasaKazi • Internship • Feb 2023 - Apr 2023

## **Digital Marketing Specialist**

- Conducted extensive keyword research to identify target keywords and optimize the website content to improve organic search rankings
- Optimized copy across the website and landing pages for better visibility.
- · Perform research on industry trends, target audience preferences, and competitor activities

# **Independent Electoral and Boundaries Commission •** Part-time • Jul 2022 - Aug 2022 **Deputy Presiding Officer**

- Delivered reliable and credible election results by ensuring 100% accuracy in the counting and tallying of votes.
- Maintained a perfect record in the safe storage and safeguarding of all entrusted election documents, materials, and equipment.
- Improved the election process by 15% through effective oversight and management.

## Kenya National Bureau of Statistics • Part-time • Nov 2019 - Feb 2020

# **Research Assistant**

- Administered research questionnaires in-person to 200 participants over a 3-month period with an 85% response rate.
- Gathered additional data for validation purposes by following up with respondents.
- Submitted daily reports to the supervisor with 100% accuracy and good timeliness.

## Safaricom Limited • Full-time • Aug 2018 - Oct 2019

#### Sales Representative

• Offered product information and advice to 50+ customers daily, resulting in customer satisfaction.

- Directed the project of a building acquisition, completing all documentation accurately and within the required timeline.
- Guided 30+ customers per week on the payment procedure and informed them about new products.

#### **EDUCATION**

# **Bachelor of Science in Statistics and Programming in Statistics**

Machakos University • Machakos • Sep 2014 - Nov 2018

#### **CERTIFICATIONS**

# Google Data analytics Certificate

Google • Feb 2021 - Jul 2021

# Nanodegree in Data Analytics

Udacity • Jul 2022 - Oct 2023

#### **SKILLS**

Managing projects efficiently, Providing exceptional customer service and support, Proficient in Microsoft Office Suite, R, Data Visualization using Tableau and PowerBi, Solving complex problems with creative solutions, Python, Data Mining and Data cleaning, Communicating effectively both verbally and in writing, SQL, SEO Awareness, Content Creation and Copywriting